[
    {
        "question":"\\text{universal law of gravitation}",
        "answer":"F\\;=\\frac{\\;Gm_1m_2}{R^2}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{universal law of gravitation vectorially}",
        "answer":"F\\;=\\frac{\\;Gm_1m_2}{R^3}.\\vec{R}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{mass of earth}",
        "answer":"5.97\\times10^{24}kg"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{radius of earth}",
        "answer":"6400km"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{accelaeration due to gravity at height}",
        "answer":"g_h\\;=\\;\\frac{GM}{(R+h)^2}\\;or\\;g_h\\;=\\;g_s(1-\\frac{2h}{R})"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{accelaeration due to gravity at depth}",
        "answer":"g_d\\;=\\;\\frac{g_sr}{R}\\;or\\;g_d\\;=\\;g_s(1-\\frac{d}{R})"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{varition in g due to rotation}",
        "answer":"g\\prime\\;=\\;g-R\\omega^2cos\\theta"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational field}",
        "answer":"\\vec{E}\\;=\\;\\frac{\\vec{F}}{m}\\;or\\;\\vec{E}\\;=\\;\\frac{Gm}{R^2}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational field due to rod}",
        "answer":"\\vec{E}\\;=\\;\\frac{GM}{a(L+a)}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational field due to ring}",
        "answer":"\\vec{E}\\;=\\;\\frac{GMx}{(R^2+x^2)^{\\frac{3}{2}}}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational field due to hollow sphere(inside,outside,at surface)}",
        "answer":"\\vec{E}_{in}=zero\\;,\\;\\vec{E}_{surface}=\\frac{Gm}{R^2}\\,\\vec{E}_{out}=\\frac{Gm}{r^2}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational field due to solid sphere(inside,outside,at surface)}",
        "answer":"\\vec{E}_{in}=\\frac{Gmr}{R^3}\\;,\\;\\vec{E}_{surface}=\\frac{Gm}{R^2}\\;,\\vec{E}_{out}=\\frac{Gm}{r^2}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational field due to infinite long wire}",
        "answer":"g\\;=\\;\\frac{2G\\lambda}{r}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational potential(V)}",
        "answer":"V\\;=\\;-\\frac{GM}{r}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational potential due to ring}",
        "answer":"-\\frac{GM}{\\sqrt{R^2+x^2}}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational potential due to hollow sphere(inside,outside,at surface)}",
        "answer":"v_{in}\\;=\\;-\\frac{GM}{R}\\;,\\;v_{sur}\\;=\\;-\\frac{GM}{R}\\;,\\;v_{out}\\;=\\;-\\frac{GM}{r}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational potential due to solid sphere(inside,outside,at surface)}",
        "answer":"v_{in}\\;=\\;-\\frac{3GM}{2R}[1-\\frac{r^2}{3R^2}]\\;or\\;\\frac{GM(3R^2-r^2)}{2R^3}\\;,\\;v_{sur}\\;=\\;-\\frac{GM}{R}\\;,\\;v_{out}\\;=\\;-\\frac{GM}{r}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{relation betwen gravi. field and gravi. potential}",
        "answer":"E\\;=\\;-\\frac{dv}{dr}\\;or\\;v\\;=\\;-\\int E.dr"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{gravitational potential energy}",
        "answer":"U\\;=\\;-\\frac{GM_1M_2}{r}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{self gravitational potential energy of sphere(hollow,solid)}",
        "answer":"U_{hollow}\\;=\\;\\frac{3}{5}\\frac{GM^2}{R}\\;and\\;U_{solid}\\;=\\;\\frac{1}{2}\\frac{GM^2}{R}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{escape velocity}",
        "answer":"V_e\\;=\\;\\sqrt{\\frac{2GM}{R}}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{orbital velocity}",
        "answer":"V_o\\;=\\;\\sqrt{\\frac{GM}{r}}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{time period of a satellite}",
        "answer":"t\\;=\\;\\frac{2\\pi R^{\\frac{3}{2}}}{\\sqrt{GM}}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{kinetic energy of a satellite}",
        "answer":"KE\\;=\\;\\frac{GMm}{2r}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{potential energy of a satellite}",
        "answer":"PE\\;=\\;-\\frac{GMm}{r}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{total energy of a satellite}",
        "answer":"TE\\;=\\;-\\frac{GMm}{2r}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{height of geo-stationary satellite}",
        "answer":"3600\\;km"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{height of polar-stationary satellite}",
        "answer":"500-800\\;km"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{according to keplers 2nd law dA/dt=?}",
        "answer":"\\frac{L}{2m}"
    }
]
